

Daniel Calderon

Profile

Experienced, determined, and quick-learning drywall/lathing apprentice with over 5 years of experience in the construction industry. Holds a track record of successfully working as part of a team for multi-million dollar building projects across Northern California. Knowledgeable in RFIs and blueprint technology. Experienced in installing gypsum board, rough framing, and OSHA regulations, as well as safe working practices. A diligent worker who can problem solve and improvise under short deadlines and communicate with a multitude of trades throughout job sites.

Employment History

Drywall/Framing apprentice at Performance Contracting inc., Sacramento

May 2022 — Present

- Worked within teams to safely follow job-specific rules and complete building assignments within a set time frame.
- Utilized my skills and knowledge of carpentry to build load-bearing and non-load bearing walls
- Followed blueprints and revisions accordingly.
- Used safe working practices at all times, and followed company guidelines.

Drywall/Framing Apprentice at California Drywall co, South San Francisco

January 2021 — September 2021

- Constructed shaft walls, rough framing, installed gypsum board, and suspended t-bar ceilings
- Conducted safety practices while using powder-actuated tools.
- Used aerial lift and safety equipment to complete exterior framing
- Learned layout of different interior wall systems prior to construction.
- Maintained job site cleanliness daily and completed job hazard analysts to identify, mitigate, and eliminate safety hazards.
- Apprentice Leadman in charge of setting up crews and overseeing production quality

Drywall/Framing Apprentice at Raymond Interior Inc., Davis

September 2006 — March 2008

- Worked with an exterior crew to complete framing and gypsum sheathing.
- Utilized safety measures while working within scaffolding.
- Knowledge of hot work permits and fire control measures.
- Learned to install exterior insulation and steel metal decking.

Details

Sacramento United States 9168962438

Danielcalderon1199@gmail.com

Skills

Drywall/Commercial Framing Systems

Welding

Trade Safety

Knowledge of Power Tools and Safety Equipment

Mathematical Skills

Blueprint Reading Skills

Languages

Spanish

English

Drywall/Framing Appentice at Standard Drywall Inc., Oakland

January 2018 — October 2018

- Installed interior and exterior gypsum board.
- Framed elevator shafts and transported material throughout the job site.
- Worked as a team to keep job site cleanliness high and helped crews maintain safe work practices.

Education

Associate in Drywall/Lathing Appenticeship, American River College, Sacramento

June 2018 — Present

• 42 credits with a GPA - 3.72

High School Diploma, Elk Grove High School, Elk Grove

August 2013 — May 2017

◄ References

References available upon request